<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Random Bits]]></title>
  <link href="http://whytheplatypus.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://whytheplatypus.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-14T18:03:24-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://whytheplatypus.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Gage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[VMWare support coming to Vagrant]]></title>
    <link href="http://whytheplatypus.github.com/blog/2013/03/14/vmware-support-coming-to-vagrant/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-14T17:14:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://whytheplatypus.github.com/blog/2013/03/14/vmware-support-coming-to-vagrant</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/58059557">Looks like VMWare support</a> is coming to <a href="http://www.vagrantup.com/">Vagrant</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.vagrantup.com/">Vagrant</a> was mentioned on WeBWorK&#8217;s devel list awhile back as a possiblilty for easy dev installs for our developers.  At the time I looked at it and decided against putting energy into it because I thought VitrualBox was kind of clunky (I have no argument or evidence to support that by the way…) and the stand alone DMG we had worked well enough for a quick mac dev distro.<br/>
I&#8217;ve been using VMWare to play with SmartOS for awhile, I&#8217;ve also got a couple ubuntu WeBWorK installs on it, and I really like it so far.</p>

<p>If <a href="http://www.vagrantup.com/">Vagrant</a> is going to support it and, possibly even more exciting, <a href="http://www.hashicorp.com/blog/preview-vagrant-aws.html">cloud options</a> I think it could become an extreamly useful tool for WeBWorK developers and maybe even for the folks managing WeBWorK installs around the world.</p>

<p>It looks like these new features are set to land sometime in the middle of March, so I&#8217;ll keep an eye on it and hopfull have some setups for WeBWorK soon after it&#8217;s available.</p>

<p>~WhyThePlatypus</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[openwebwork at Raleigh]]></title>
    <link href="http://whytheplatypus.github.com/blog/2013/03/13/openwebwork-at-raleigh/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-13T15:38:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://whytheplatypus.github.com/blog/2013/03/13/openwebwork-at-raleigh</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We just finished up another webwork code camp, WeBWorK::Raleigh::2013.<br/>
It&#8217;s always such a blast, especially when we get to work in such a nice environment. The NC State math building is fantastic.</p>

<p>We&#8217;re trying out a new workflow based on <a href="https://github.com/nvie/gitflow">git flow</a> that Djun Kim and Davide Cervone put together.  There should be a write up for it up on the <a href="http://webwork.maa.org/wiki/Main_Page">wiki</a> in the next few days if there aren&#8217;t already.  It looks like it will be much easier to maintain&#8230; of course coming from what we were doing that&#8217;s not a hard sell.</p>

<p>The main thing I&#8217;m excited about is getting a new WeBWorK API written down.  If we can standardise how we send requests and what data we&#8217;re guarenteed to get back then a new back end and as many apps and tools that tie into it as we want wont be far behind.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s the <a href="https://github.com/openwebwork/WeBWorK-API">API so far</a>. Any and all pull requests, forks, and suggestions help!  The idea is to specify what the request and response will be at a minimum so that applications can use it knowing what to expect at the least, but without limiting them to only what&#8217;s in the API.</p>

<p>oh! Djun also set up <a href="http://openwebwork.org">openwebwork.org</a>.  It&#8217;s really nice to have a good looking face for the project :)</p>

<p>~WhyThePlatypus</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting up mDNS on SmartOS]]></title>
    <link href="http://whytheplatypus.github.com/blog/2013/02/01/setting-up-mdns-on-smartos/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-01T09:36:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://whytheplatypus.github.com/blog/2013/02/01/setting-up-mdns-on-smartos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been working with smartOS alot through VMWare Fusion on my macbook.  I was getting sick of looking up IP addresses so I poked around and sure enough mdns was there the whole time..</p>

<p>It took me a bit to figure out how to enable it on the VMs, turns out it&#8217;s straightforward. Just running this in a VM should do it.</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/whytheplatypus/4692693.js"></script>


<p>I also put together a quick script to let me make and name new nodes quickly.</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/whytheplatypus/4692705.js"></script>


<p>enjoy!</p>

<p>~WhyThePlatypus</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
